<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>CJKinni.com</title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<link href="https://cjkinni.com" rel="self" />
	<id>https://cjkinni.com</id>
	<updated>2021-04-10T05:00:00.Z</updated>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>rebeccapurple and the many colors of CSS</title>
		<link href="/words/2021-04-10-rebeccapurple-and-the-many-colors-of-css.html" />
		<id>/words/2021-04-10-rebeccapurple-and-the-many-colors-of-css.html</id>
		<updated>2021-04-10T05:00:00.Z</updated>
		<content>
			<p>When I was coding up this website, I realized I tend to spend a great deal of time <a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/yak_shaving">yak shaving</a> any time I had to pick a color.  There's something about the process of finding a color that I find completely bewildering.  I've tried, more times than I can count, and it's just not for me.</p><p>So when I was writing the CSS, I quickly decided to remind myself what the default colors for CSS were.  I don't think I'd looked at the colors seriously since it was just the default sixteen:</p><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: black;">black</span><span style="color: silver;">silver</span><span style="color: gray;">gray</span><span style="color: white;">white</span><span style="color: maroon;">maroon</span><span style="color: red;">red</span><span style="color: purple;">purple</span><span style="color: fuchsia;">fuchsia</span><span style="color: green;">green</span><span style="color: lime;">lime</span><span style="color: olive;">olive</span><span style="color: yellow;">yellow</span><span style="color: navy;">navy</span><span style="color: blue;">blue</span><span style="color: teal;">teal</span><span style="color: aqua;">aqua</span></div><p>These were all there were from <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/CSS1/">their specification</a> in 1996 untill 2011.  15 years later, we'd receive the next color addition in <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/CSS2/">CSS Level 2 Rev 1</a>:</p><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: orange;">orange</span></div><p>That's right.  Orange.  The seventeenth named color.</p><p>Since then, the colors have gone in an excellent direction.  No longer catering to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_Graphics_Array">VTA</a> displays, they're less bold, and more subtle.  Their names are also excellent.  On <a href="https://drafts.csswg.org/css-color-3/">March 2018</a>, we'd get this wonderful selection of 129 colors</p><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: aliceblue;">aliceblue</span><span style="color: antiquewhite;">antiquewhite</span><span style="color: aquamarine;">aquamarine</span><span style="color: azure;">azure</span><span style="color: beige;">beige</span><span style="color: bisque;">bisque</span><span style="color: blanchedalmond;">blanchedalmond</span><span style="color: blueviolet;">blueviolet</span><span style="color: brown;">brown</span><span style="color: burlywood;">burlywood</span><span style="color: cadetblue;">cadetblue</span><span style="color: chartreuse;">chartreuse</span><span style="color: chocolate;">chocolate</span><span style="color: coral;">coral</span><span style="color: cornflowerblue;">cornflowerblue</span><span style="color: cornsilk;">cornsilk</span><span style="color: crimson;">crimson</span><span style="color: cyan;">cyan</span><span style="color: darkblue;">darkblue</span><span style="color: darkcyan;">darkcyan</span><span style="color: darkgoldenrod;">darkgoldenrod</span><span style="color: darkgray;">darkgray</span><span style="color: darkgreen;">darkgreen</span><span style="color: darkgrey;">darkgrey</span><span style="color: darkkhaki;">darkkhaki</span><span style="color: darkmagenta;">darkmagenta</span><span style="color: darkolivegreen;">darkolivegreen</span><span style="color: darkorange;">darkorange</span><span style="color: darkorchid;">darkorchid</span><span style="color: darkred;">darkred</span><span style="color: darksalmon;">darksalmon</span><span style="color: darkseagreen;">darkseagreen</span><span style="color: darkslateblue;">darkslateblue</span><span style="color: darkslategray;">darkslategray</span><span style="color: darkslategrey;">darkslategrey</span><span style="color: darkturquoise;">darkturquoise</span><span style="color: darkviolet;">darkviolet</span><span style="color: deeppink;">deeppink</span><span style="color: deepskyblue;">deepskyblue</span><span style="color: dimgray;">dimgray</span><span style="color: dimgrey;">dimgrey</span><span style="color: dodgerblue;">dodgerblue</span><span style="color: firebrick;">firebrick</span><span style="color: floralwhite;">floralwhite</span><span style="color: forestgreen;">forestgreen</span><span style="color: gainsboro;">gainsboro</span><span style="color: ghostwhite;">ghostwhite</span><span style="color: gold;">gold</span><span style="color: goldenrod;">goldenrod</span><span style="color: greenyellow;">greenyellow</span><span style="color: grey;">grey</span><span style="color: honeydew;">honeydew</span><span style="color: hotpink;">hotpink</span><span style="color: indianred;">indianred</span><span style="color: indigo;">indigo</span><span style="color: ivory;">ivory</span><span style="color: khaki;">khaki</span><span style="color: lavender;">lavender</span><span style="color: lavenderblush;">lavenderblush</span><span style="color: lawngreen;">lawngreen</span><span style="color: lemonchiffon;">lemonchiffon</span><span style="color: lightblue;">lightblue</span><span style="color: lightcoral;">lightcoral</span><span style="color: lightcyan;">lightcyan</span><span style="color: lightgoldenrodyellow;">lightgoldenrodyellow</span><span style="color: lightgray;">lightgray</span><span style="color: lightgreen;">lightgreen</span><span style="color: lightgrey;">lightgrey</span><span style="color: lightpink;">lightpink</span><span style="color: lightsalmon;">lightsalmon</span><span style="color: lightseagreen;">lightseagreen</span><span style="color: lightskyblue;">lightskyblue</span><span style="color: lightslategray;">lightslategray</span><span style="color: lightslategrey;">lightslategrey</span><span style="color: lightsteelblue;">lightsteelblue</span><span style="color: lightyellow;">lightyellow</span><span style="color: limegreen;">limegreen</span><span style="color: linen;">linen</span><span style="color: magenta;">magenta</span><span style="color: mediumaquamarine;">mediumaquamarine</span><span style="color: mediumblue;">mediumblue</span><span style="color: mediumorchid;">mediumorchid</span><span style="color: mediumpurple;">mediumpurple</span><span style="color: mediumseagreen;">mediumseagreen</span><span style="color: mediumslateblue;">mediumslateblue</span><span style="color: mediumspringgreen;">mediumspringgreen</span><span style="color: mediumturquoise;">mediumturquoise</span><span style="color: mediumvioletred;">mediumvioletred</span><span style="color: midnightblue;">midnightblue</span><span style="color: mintcream;">mintcream</span><span style="color: mistyrose;">mistyrose</span><span style="color: moccasin;">moccasin</span><span style="color: navajowhite;">navajowhite</span><span style="color: oldlace;">oldlace</span><span style="color: olivedrab;">olivedrab</span><span style="color: orangered;">orangered</span><span style="color: orchid;">orchid</span><span style="color: palegoldenrod;">palegoldenrod</span><span style="color: palegreen;">palegreen</span><span style="color: paleturquoise;">paleturquoise</span><span style="color: palevioletred;">palevioletred</span><span style="color: papayawhip;">papayawhip</span><span style="color: peachpuff;">peachpuff</span><span style="color: peru;">peru</span><span style="color: pink;">pink</span><span style="color: plum;">plum</span><span style="color: powderblue;">powderblue</span><span style="color: rosybrown;">rosybrown</span><span style="color: royalblue;">royalblue</span><span style="color: saddlebrown;">saddlebrown</span><span style="color: salmon;">salmon</span><span style="color: sandybrown;">sandybrown</span><span style="color: seagreen;">seagreen</span><span style="color: seashell;">seashell</span><span style="color: sienna;">sienna</span><span style="color: skyblue;">skyblue</span><span style="color: slateblue;">slateblue</span><span style="color: slategray;">slategray</span><span style="color: slategrey;">slategrey</span><span style="color: snow;">snow</span><span style="color: springgreen;">springgreen</span><span style="color: steelblue;">steelblue</span><span style="color: tan;">tan</span><span style="color: thistle;">thistle</span><span style="color: tomato;">tomato</span><span style="color: turquoise;">turquoise</span><span style="color: violet;">violet</span><span style="color: wheat;">wheat</span><span style="color: whitesmoke;">whitesmoke</span><span style="color: yellowgreen;">yellowgreen</span></div><p>Most recently we added one more color:</p><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: rebeccapurple;">rebeccapurple</span></div><p>This color is why I wrote this whole post.  I won't repeat the story, but please give <a href="https://codepen.io/trezy/post/honoring-a-great-man">this short explanation of the color and what it honors</a> a read.  I must admit, I didn't expect to get teary while reading about CSS color options.</p>
		</content>
		<author>
			<name>CJKinni</name>
			<email>chris@cjkinni.com</email>
		</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A simple static site generator in Elixir</title>
		<link href="/words/2021-04-09-a-simple-static-site-generator-in-elixir.html" />
		<id>/words/2021-04-09-a-simple-static-site-generator-in-elixir.html</id>
		<updated>2021-04-09T05:00:00.Z</updated>
		<content>
			<p>Inspired in large part by <a href="https://twitter.com/code_report">Conor Hoekstra</a>, I've been getting more into functional programming over the past few months.  I've been consuming a lot of functional programming content, and tryign to work more pure functions into my programming, but until this week, I haven't spent much time doing development in a functional language.</p><p>This week, I've built two working things in <a href="https://elixir-lang.org">Elixir</a>.  </p><p>First, there's a proxy server to assist me in developing against heavily ratelimited APIs.  It's using Phoenix, and I had it up in running from never having written a line of Elixir in about six hours (much of which was spent navigating RFCs to make sure I completely understood how HTTP and HTTPs proxies work.)</p><p>Second, is the <a href="https://github.com/CJKinni/BlogEngine">little tool</a> I'm using to generate <a href="https://github.com/CJKinni/cjkinni.github.io">this site</a>.  It's basically a MVP static-site generator.  That is, it takes a folder of <a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> formatted documents and spits out a table of context and some nicely formatted blog posts.  Eventually I'll add an Atom feed, and maybe some other nice features.  This was an evening project today, and it took about two hours while watching TV with Laura.  It's <em>very</em> janky, but it's also <em>very</em> simple, which I like.</p><p>It basically consists of a few files:</p><p>/lib/blog_engine.ex:</p><p>This consists of nine simple helper functions that do various things like delete all the files in a directory, get a directory list, parse a blogpost, and render the templates.  There are some hardcoded paths I'd like to move out of the tool, but I think it's fine for now.</p><p>/build.ex:</p><p>This is where the magic happens.  It's almost exclusively written using the <code class="inline">|></code> pipe operator, and passing lists through a bunch of functions that do the real work.  I'm not sure this is ideal, but it's really simple to think about composing these little functions like this.  It deletes the last version of the site, re-generates from the source files, and replaces any deleted static files I want.</p><p>/generate.sh:</p><p>This runs /build.ex, then commits changes to both my BlogEngine repository and the repository that runs CJKinni.com, so that the changes will go live on CJKinni.com within a few minutes.</p><p>I enjoyed writing the code.  It's very straightforward, and I <em>think</em> that it will be easier to return to than some of the other coding projects I've taken breaks from.</p><p>I'm still not sure what the result of my deep dive into category theory will be, but for now I'm enjoying the ride.</p>
		</content>
		<author>
			<name>CJKinni</name>
			<email>chris@cjkinni.com</email>
		</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Pneumonia II</title>
		<link href="/words/2021-04-08-pneumonia-ii.html" />
		<id>/words/2021-04-08-pneumonia-ii.html</id>
		<updated>2021-04-08T05:00:00.Z</updated>
		<content>
			<p><a href="/words/pneumonia-I.html">Last time</a>, I described my hospital stay after a surprise pneumonia diagnosis. Unfortunately, I wish that was the end of the troubles.</p><p>I wasn't getting better.  I was told to check in with my primary care doctor, who I actually hadn't met in person after moving over to her early in the Pandemic.</p><p>Great introduction: "Hi Doc, I have pneumonia, and I feel like crap."</p><p>So she talks to me for a bit, and decides that after the course of antibiotics I've taken, I should feel great.  So on to antibiotic treatment round two! And this time, she lets me know that if I'm still feeling like shit by Friday, then I need to come back and talk to her again.</p><p>Well, the past few days have been miserable.</p><p>I don't love talking about the specifics of my job, but I think I want to tell a bit of a story, mostly to contextualize why today feels worse than spending eighteen hours as a roomate of a delusional man going thorugh withdrawals while in the worst pain of his life.</p><p>I'm responsible for a fairly large piece of infrastructure at work. After it was performing poorly a few years ago, I took a month to do a top-to-bottom rewrite of the service, and now it is something all our business runs through.  We have a third party dependency that has been extremely flaky as we've increased the ammount we use it, and sometimes it cuts out completely.  Over the past month, this has lead to processes that usually take minutes to take hours, which is far from ideal. Acknowledged.</p><p>Early last week, I took up the task of doing everything in my power to get this system under control.  I read a bunch of newly released documentaiton on our dependency, made a ton of updates and improvements to the system, and was realy proud of the job I'd done.</p><p>The evening I released the big fix was the night before I went into the hospital.  That next morning, I was messaging my boss to make sure the system was up and running, since I couldn't get onto our VPN from my phone, but it was practically the first weekday in a month that I hadn't had urgent alerts pinging my phone (which I should get even if I wasn't on the VPN.)</p><p>The fix had worked.  While I was in the hospital, a colleague (who didn't know I was out) pinged me to let me know that the test servers were running very quickly, and he was appreciative.</p><p>Throughout the hospital stay, the one thing I was really hanging onto was how pleased I was that I'd managed to resolve this debilitating crisis at work.  I imagined going into the Thrusday meeting and saying that it was the first calm week in a while, and everyone being pretty pleased they'd no longer be receiving alerts about the system going down.</p><p>Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday go by swimmingly, and lasst night I released a new update.</p><p>I still haven't figured out exactly what happened, or even if the update had anything to do with it, but on Thursday morning three services we rely on that seemed to all go down at once under some heavy load.  And the system was backed up for hours processing the backlog.</p><p>So today, instead of coming into the Thursday meeting a hero, I was panicing while I tried to fix the crisis, while running back and forth to the bathroom with nausea.  It sucked. It was all pretty much resolved by the Thursday meeting I'd been excited about just a day before.  But the meeting was awful.  There was a mini-lecture from a co-worker (who only knows about the system, and not the pneumonia or anything else).  Everything that was brought up was fair, and logical, and reasonable.  But I am glad the meeting was remote so I could just shut up, mute myself, and not have anyone looking at my face.</p><p>So that was today.  I was nauseous, couldn't eat, fucked up at work, and was reminded of it.</p><p>Tomorrow, if I'm not somehow feeling better, I check back in with the Doctor and you get a Pneumonia III.</p>
		</content>
		<author>
			<name>CJKinni</name>
			<email>chris@cjkinni.com</email>
		</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Pneumonia I</title>
		<link href="/words/2021-04-07-pneumonia-i.html" />
		<id>/words/2021-04-07-pneumonia-i.html</id>
		<updated>2021-04-07T05:00:00.Z</updated>
		<content>
			<p>It's been a rough couple months.  The title probably gives away the punchline.</p><p>My son started daycare a couple months ago, and soon after my wife and I picked up bit of a cold.  Of course, mine just wouldn't go away.  After two covid tests and six weeks of a lingering cough that had my sinuses rioting, my doctor prescribed me some antibiotics for sinusitis.</p><p>I was in good spirits, and I did start to improve.  The sinus issues were gone, and I thought I was mostly in the clear.</p><p>After a pretty good week, I woke up last Wednesday to my whole body shaking.  We've had some furnace issues this winter, and I thought it might have gone out again.  But I was shaking too much to get up and do anything about it, and I quickly woke up Laura who let me know it wasn't cold at all.</p><p>Great. I was shaking pretty badly now -- like my hands were moving back and forth maybe an inch and a half with each shake.  My mind was fine though, and I made some jokes to try and lighten the mood while she got a thermometer and called a nurse line.</p><p>The nurse told me to go to the emergency room.  I was in no state to drive, so at 5 AM Laura woke up our son, bundled him up, and dropped me off at the ER, thinking she'd be picking me up later that day.</p><p>After meeting with a doctor, my fever broke and the shaking let up. The doctor took some blood, and I got a bit of sleep before a large, portable X-Ray machine was wheeled into my room and took some shots of my chest.</p><p>A little more waiting, and they knew what it was: I had pneumonia.  The shaking was <a href="<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chills%22%3Erigors%3C/a%3E,">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chills">rigors</a>,</a> caused from the pneumonia.  Since the reaction was fairly severe, they reccomended I spend a day in the hospital to ensure everything was alright before I came home in the morning. I agreed, and was given some intravenous antibiotics, and wheeled up to my new home for the next 36 hours.</p><p>On the whole, roommate Number One was pretty good company.  He was a deaf older man accompanied by his daughter, as he went through some tests of his balance.  He did an unintentionally hilarious bit where he refused to do any of the tests because they seemed more dangerous than not performing the tests, and it would hurt if he fell.  He spoke pretty loudly, but I couldn't complain too much, at least it was something to listen to as I was laying in the hospital bed, hooked into an IV.</p><p>He left in the afternoon, and I had a nice few hours to myself.  The night nurse told me I'd probably have the place to myself for the evening.  I enjoyed the few hours I had to sleep alone before roommate number two was wheeled in, screaming.</p><p>Roommate Number Two had a rough life.  A little over fifty, he'd been in and out of the hospital a few times.  This time, he'd broken his eye-socket and arm while passed out.  It looked like it hurt, and the withdrawals over the next 18 hours I'd spend with Number Two sounded equally unpleasant.</p><p>The 'goals' listed on the board for my hospital stay were 'antibiotics' and 'rest.'  I certainly got more of one than the other.  I might have slept two hours after Number Two entered my life.  When he wasn't yelling, he was talking to people that weren't there, and twice peed on the floor.</p><p>As I said, he was going through a lot.  He tried his best to be kind and appreciative of the nurses, and was appreciative when I helped him with his breakfast.  But I can't say that I entirely enjoyed my stay.</p><p>When morning came, I was anxious to see the doctor and get out of the hospital.  Unfortunately, as I was told by my nurse, "the Doctor comes when the Doctor comes."  My wife and I re-scheduled when she'd pick me up throughout the day, pushing our expectations back later and later.  Dispite being on a few hours sleep, I kept awake, afraid that I'd sleep through the Doctor doing her rounds.</p><p>A little after 4 pm, and 36 hours since I came to the ER, I was let out, and given some antibiotics to take.</p><p>It felt great to be home.  I was in good spirits.  But I didn't start to improve...</p><p><a href="/words/pneumonia-II.html">II</a></p>
		</content>
		<author>
			<name>CJKinni</name>
			<email>chris@cjkinni.com</email>
		</author>
	

</feed>